fotopages.com 2010-01-18

# Privacy policy - Photo blogging made easy - Fotopages.com

**Privacy policy**  
**Privacy Statement for Fotopages  
Last Revised October 20, 2003 **

We at Fotopages have a firm commitment to safeguarding the privacy of our users. This page will inform you about our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Fotopages service. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should contact support@fotopages.com. 

**In General**

Fotopages provides you with a way to create and share your photolog with others. Fotopages includes a directory and search feature allowing members of the public to access Fotopages that are listed in the directory. All new Fotopages are automatically included in the directory. In order to remove your Fotopage from the directory, use the checkbox in the Settings tab once you have logged in. However, removing your Fotopage from the directory does not guarantee the privacy of your Fotopage, it just means that it is not viewable on the homepage, via the search function, or via the browse by username or country functions. 

**Your Personal Information**

Fotopages only uses your personal information to conduct business with you. Your personally identifiable information will not be rented, sold or shared with any third party, except as described in this Privacy Statement or as otherwise agreed by you. Fotopages may disclose information it has collected from any member of the Fotopages Service and/or content any member has made available on the Fotopages Service when it believes in good faith that the law or legal process requires it, or when it is necessary to do so to protect the rights or property of Fotopages or others. 

Fotopages may change this privacy policy without notice from time to time. Please visit this page often for updates and changes. 

**Information We Collect and How We Use It**

In order to establish your account you will be asked to provide certain personally identifiable information to us, such as your name, email address, country, and zip code. We will use that information to communicate with you directly via email. We may also ask you for similar information, and information about your photography equipment and practices, if you choose to request a newsletter, enter a contest, fill out a customer survey or participate in a program. We may use this information to make improvements on our site, offer new products, and customize your experience on the Fotopages Web site. We use aggregate non-personal information (i.e. information that does not include personally identifiable data) for statistical analysis of user behavior, product development, content improvement and marketing, promotional and advertising purposes. We may also make that aggregate non-personal information available to select third party partners. 

**Information We Automatically Collect**

Generally speaking, we use cookies to track users of the Fotopages Service. For example, when you visit our site, we assign you a unique User ID and store it on your computer in the form of a cookie (unless your browser's cookie support has been disabled). Through the use of cookies and User IDs we are able to optimize the performance and functionality of our site, and to personalize our site for you and present you with content and offers specific to your interests. 

**Disabling Cookies**

The Fotopages web site uses cookies to store session information and will not work unless cookies are enabled. 

**IP Address**

We analyze IP addresses in the aggregate for system administration purposes and to gather broad demographic information. We do not link IP addresses to your computer's User ID, with the following exception: if you place an order using our online checkout process we record your computer's IP address with your order to help us identify fraudulent credit card use. We may share this information with the financial institution that issued the credit card with which an order was placed, or with law enforcement authorities if we determine, or are notified, that the use of the credit card was fraudulent. Your information will only be shared in this instance when you affirmatively choose to complete the Fotopages order form contained in the Fotopages shopping cart. 

**Affiliate Site ID**

If you entered Fotopages Web site by clicking a link or promotion on another Web site (including a Fotopages co-branded portion of another Web site), or if you used a site that provides universal registration services to sign up for the Fotopages site, we will store the ID of that affiliate site in our database along with your computer's User ID. We do this to ensure that the affiliate site receives proper credit for any subsequent order you might place. We may also use this information in conjunction with your activities on our site to help us identify what offers and services may be of interest to you. 

**Information Sharing**

We may share your personally identifiable information with those companies that assist us in providing the Fotopages Service to you. Following are some examples of our use of third party service providers: We may share your credit card information with a financial institution to effect your purchase of our products using your credit card. We may share personally identifiable information (not including credit card information) with third parties that assist us with the administration of our newsletters or contests or that help us understand the results of particular surveys we may perform. We may also engage third parties to assist us by tracking the number of visitors to our Web site, including visitors that have "clicked-through" from specified promotions on third party Web sites and those visitors' activities on the site. We may also choose to offer certain third party products through the Fotopages Service and may disclose certain portions of your personally identifiable information (not including credit card information) to allow those product producers to fulfill your product order. 

**Your Copyrights**

Fotopages respects the intellectual property rights of others. Fotopages claims no ownership rights in any image contained in any of your photologs. 

**Opting-Out and Updates**

The Fotopages Service provides you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving newsletters and other communications from Fotopages. To discontinue your receipt of such newsletters and communications, you can do so in the "Settings" portion of the "My Account" section of Fotopages Web site. Nonetheless, Fotopages will continue to send you non-promotional, service emails concerning your account. 

If you want to review or change any information you previously provided to us, please go to the "Settings" portion of the "My Account" section of the site. 

**De-Activating Your Fotopages Account**

If you want to de-activate your account with Fotopages, please send an email to support@fotopages.com with your request. Please be sure to include the username and email address of the account you wish to de-activate. Your account will be de-activated and you will no longer receive communications from us; however, we will keep your account information in our database for record-keeping purposes only. 

**Links to Other Sites**

This site may contain links to other sites. Fotopages is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other Web sites. 

**Questions about the Fotopages Service**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of the Fotopages Service, or your dealings with us, you can email your questions to support@fotopages.com
